OKAFOR EMELDER

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

I am a frontend developer with demonstrated experience in building scalable websites by translating UI/UX design wireframes into maintainable and responsive user interface using JavaScript(ES6), React/API, CSS and CSS frameworks, HTML, Git and other technologies for developing interactive frontend applications. I'm a fast learner, a team player and can work independently on any task to arrive at a workable and most profitable end point.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Frontend Developer - Freelancer

2021-Present

- Designing effective, maintainable and scalable user interfaces for clients and brands.
- Maintaining, troubleshooting and updating websites according to new design requirements to boost performance.
- Collaborating with clients to define solution requirements for applicable development variables.
- Transforming UI/UX wireframes into interactive and responsive websites.

Junior Frontend Developer Ascendancy, Lagos, Nigeria

2019-2021

Identified and implemented dynamic web solutions in accordance to company standards and best practices.

- Partnered with UI/UX design teams to transform clients wireframes from conception to implementation.
- Assisted the development team in developing 5 WordPress sites with testing, deployment and updates.
- Worked in an agile environment with weekly stand-ups, kept track
 of user stories/bugs in GitHub projects and conducted 2 hours of
 sprint planning and sprint retrospectives per week.

Software Engineer - Full Time

2017 - 2019

Rural Electrification Agency of Nigeria

- Tested and maintained recommended software improvements.
- Renewable energy system installations
- Researching, designing, implementing and managing software programs.
- Identifying areas for modification in existing programs and subsequently developing these modifications.

CONTACT

- +234-80375-88098
- github.com/meldy2503/
- emelder-okafor-portfolio.com
- (in) linkedin.com/in/emelder-okafor

SKILLS

- HTML/HTML5
- CSS/CSS3
- JavaScript(ES6)
- React/Context API
- Material-UI
- Styled-components
- Tailwind-CSS
- SASS
- Bootstrap
- Redux
- WordPress

Tools

- Git/Github/Gitlab/BitBucket
- Figma/ Zeplin

Soft Skills

- Excellent communication skills in English.
- Fast learner and team player.
- Attention to details.
- Able to think fast and critically.

EDUCATION

AltSchool Africa 2022- 2023

• Diploma(Frontend Engineering)

Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Anambra State, Nigeria 2009- 2015

 B.Eng (Electrical Engineering, 2nd Class Honors-Upper Division)